Jeyavignesh Rajendran

www.github.com/jeyavigneshr

34, Gort Na Bro, Knocknacarra, Galway (353) 899-632615



jeyvigneshr1394@gmail.com www.linkedin.com/in/jey-r/



Highly skilled and innovative Machine Learning Engineer with solid academic background holding Master's degree in Artificial Intelligence and over 3 years of experience as an Application Developer with wide exposure in Software Development and Machine learning seeking to apply strong analytical, coding ability and further enhance my skills in a challenging environment.

Education

M.Sc in Artificial Intelligence / NUI Galway / 1.1(First Class)

SEP 2019 - AUG 2020

Core Modules: Machine Learning, Deep Learning, Data Visualization, Natural Language Processing, Information Retrieval, Al and Ethics

B.Tech in Information Technology / Anna University / 8.21CGPA

AUG 2012 - MAY 2016

Core Modules: Data Structures, Database and Management Systems, Software Engineering and Quality Assurance, Probability and Queuing Theory, Statistics

Projects

PROJECT 1: Procedural Content Generation using Generative Adversarial Networks

Generated game levels for the classic Super Mario game using GAN model and evolved the levels using fitness functions to generate realistic game content. The project is available on <u>mario-ui.herokuapp.com</u>.

PROJECT 2: Real-Time Object Detection using YoloV3 and Mobilenet

Designed and developed a Computer Vision pipeline using Open-CV to detect objects at real-time ad detect various features of the object. Achieved an overall accuracy of 90%.

PROJECT 3: Neural Machine Translation

Implemented a word2word NMT from English to Spanish with 89% accuracy. The model features attention to focus on input features.

Experience

Graduate Teaching Assistant & Research Intern / NUI Galway, Ireland SEP 2019 - PRESENT

- Functioned as a liaison between the professor and student by facilitating coding discussions on Education forum that enhanced exam preparedness in Java and Python.
- Currently developing a Reinforcement Learning agent to formulate an efficient pit stop strategy for Formula 1 races.

Application Developer / BNY Mellon, India

JUL 2016 – AUG 2019

- Succeeded in reducing the cost for Production support by creating a machine learning model to analyze the historical data and process complex production transactions which provided valuable insights.
- Helped the Production support teams in Root Cause Analysis (RCA) of issues by developing a text summarizer to analyze production logs which reduced the time required for analysis by 60%.

- Developed and deployed over 25+ applications as Microservices in a short span of 2 months using Agile methodology.
- Spearheaded an initiative to mitigate risk and resiliency by developing a Test automation suite to automate test cases and deployments which was later outsourced to Cognizant Technologies.
- Re-engineered ECI application, training junior associates by organizing knowledge transfer sessions.

Application Developer Trainee / BNY Mellon, Chennai, India FEB 2016 – JUN 2016

- Worked on POC(s) Car-pooling and Corporate Social Responsibility applications which were rolled out to all employees across India.
- Contributed in an Intranet application simulating stock market environment and forecast stock values to understand Financial Markets and Investment Banking domain.

Skills and Competencies

- Exceptional understanding of Computer Science fundamentals, Data Structures and algorithms backed by strong programming skills.
- Strong programming skills in Java and Python and a basic knowledge of other scripting languages such as Javascript, Node JS, Shell scripting and R language. Demonstrable experience with cluster computing using Java and Spark plug-in (Hadoop).
- Demonstrated experience with Machine Learning modelling frameworks such as TensorFlow, Keras, Scikit Learn, Open-CV and Natural Language Processing (NLP).
- Strong software engineering skills including experience of a modern agile development workflow using GIT, CI/CD tools and deployment platforms such as Google Cloud Platform and AWS.
- Experienced working with development frameworks like Spring Boot and Hibernate.
- Strong SQL experience, Mongo DB and streaming frameworks such as Apache Kafka and MQ framework Apache Camel.
- Possess advanced analytical skills and critical thinking skills needed to manage multiple often conflicting demands on a project, simultaneously
- Developing a culture of togetherness by organizing fun activities for teammates in bi-weekly meetings.

Achievements

- Awarded BNY Mellon Take a Bow thrice for delivering high quality products and making an impact on client value creation.
- Awarded BNY Mellon Bravo and Applause award for fostering teamwork and collaboration across different Line of Business.
- Was part of the very first team to re-engineer and migrate over 30 applications into Docker containers across the entire organization.
- Second Runner up at the International Students Gaelic Tournament held at the University of Limerick representing NUI Galway.

Activities

• Gaelic Football • Soccer • Formula 1 • Music